I 've been in Sta . Lucia longer than I can remember .
I heard so many stories about this place .
I 've heard so many stories
that it 's become hard to separate
the myths from the truth .
But I only know one story to be true .
Every midnight
at the end of the third floor corridor ,
beside the stairwell ,
you 'll find a comfort room .
No one dares to go there anymore .
Because if you go inside ...
there ...
when you reach the last cubicle ,
that 's where she hung herself .
Her name ...
is Erika .
Do you trust me ?
Do you know what this is ?
When I count to three ,
I want you to slam your hand here , okay ?
One ...
two ...
three !
I ordered to turn the lights off hours ago .
You must contemplate your sins in silence .
The confession will start tomorrow at 6 o 'clock sharp .
Do not be late .
Lie down !
Close your eyes !
If you cannot sleep , pray .
Be ready to confess your sins tomorrow .
Do you understand ?
Yes , Sor Alice .
Jo .
Hey , Jo . Come with me , I need to pee .
Mich ?
Come with me please , I need to pee .
Hey .
More .
Ready ...
Miss ?
Smile for the camera .
Okay , girls ,
compress .
Okay ?
Ready ?
Pat , look at this .
What a waste .
Why weren 't you smiling ?
It 's okay .
Maybe I had too much on my mind .
Especially after what happened to Anna .
Is it true ? Sor Alice found her ?
That 's what I heard from Sister Luz and Costanza .
I don 't understand why she won 't let me talk to the girl - -
Sor Alice can manage her .
But - -
Pat , you 're overthinking this .
Joyce .
They caught you on the rooftop again ?
Hand it over .
It 's already empty .
What 's this for anyway ?
To keep me awake .
Isn 't it better if you rest ?
Are you even getting any sleep ?
I should have gone with Anna .
She could still be at Sta . Lucia if I did .
Joyce ,
what happened to Anna is not your fault .
What do you think happened ?
Did she see something ?
No one 's talking about it , no one 's telling us anything .
Only Anna can tell what really happened .
I didn 't know you could leave just like that .
I wish I left a long time ago .
Why ?
It 's the same every day .
That 's why I stay on the rooftop , so I can clear my mind .
It 's as if everything 's useless , like nothing matters .
Joyce ...
are you hurting yourself again ?
Sor Alice will kill me .
- Joyce ? - I 'm late again .
You can always come here if you need someone to talk to , okay ?
This is for you , Miss Pat .
Why are you sad here again ?
That 's not me .
The Supreme Court has put Ramon Pascual on death row .
Pascual was caught in the act
decapitating the head of his mother .
Pascual is among the growing number of criminals convicted with death sentence
since it was imposed in 1993 .
Mr. Fidel .
- Good evening , Miss Consolacion . - Good evening .
Working this late again ?
As always .
You know I don 't have anyone to go home to .
Maybe you should start looking for ...
someone to go home to .
So you don 't have to work all the time .
Okay . Take care of yourself .
You too .
Good evening , Eri .
How have you been ?
I read the last book in the library .
I 've read everything .
Let 's get out of here , Miss Pat .
Where will we go ?
Anywhere .
If only I could leave this place .
Why can 't you ?
Is that what happens to people ...
like you ?
Maybe .
Do you want me to come with you ?
Eri ...
what happened to Anna ?
Did she see you ?
I didn 't mean to .
I 'm sorry .
They 're all afraid of me .
Why aren 't you ?
Should I be afraid ?
My father ...
he wasn 't afraid either .
I still see him sometimes .
There , in the corner ...
staring at me .
At us .
Where ?
Eri ?
Eri ...
Where are we going ?
Why can 't you leave ?
Is that what happens to people ...
That was the sixth session with Eri , but she still won 't tell me her story .
She needs someone to talk to ,
but she won 't tell me what really happened to her .
Why did she kill herself ?
If I knew the answer , I 'd know my students better .
I can keep them safe .
We forced her to stay late at night just to punish her .
After what happened to Anna , we should 've known better .
We all know Mr. Fidel .
He spent his whole life serving at Sta . Lucia .
Do you really believe he could do something like this ?
I 'll talk to the children .
Maybe they know something .
Sor Alice , isn 't that too soon ?
A lot of parents called - -
It 's out of our hands if they want to leave .
There are still those who chose to stay .
That 's all that matters .
Miss . Consolacion ,
may I speak with you ?
Just a moment .
Hand it over .
You 'll get into trouble again .
The matches too .
The session isn 't over yet , all right ?
Come in .
I 'm Julian . I 've been assigned to investigate this case .
How can I help you ?
You know Fidel , right ?
He was working here , even before I was hired .
Which got me thinking ...
if he 's capable of doing this , why only now ?
I 've been asking myself the same question .
Is it true you 're taking him to Muntinlupa ?
Yes .
Death row ?
I can 't say just yet .
- You also own one of these ? - Maybe there were other people
at the crime scene the night Clara was murdered .
I 'll ask around , my students might know something .
They trust me .
Good .
Use that . When you get information
useful to the investigation ...
call me .
Here 's my number .
Thank you .
Most of the conversations I have with my students are confidential .
Their secret is my secret .
I 'll call you when something comes up .
Ms. Consolacion , I 'm here to help .
We won 't tell this to the chief yet .
The chief is already convinced that Fidel did it .
Thank you .
Thank you for your time .
Clara ?
What do you think ?
How old are these butterflies ?
Butterflies only live for a few months .
They don 't look dead to me .
They look like they could still fly .
They 're not moving ...
because they are imprisoned .
I know ...
you want to talk to her .
Do you know where she is right now ?
Why would I tell you ?
You know , you can always talk to me ,
right ?
You know , Ms. Pat , you have a nice voice .
Not like my mother 's .
It 's been decades now ...
I still can 't forget my mother 's voice ...
It echoes around me ,
still ringing in my ears .
It was like how the nuns at school shouted at me .
It surrounds you , suffocates you ...
until you 're totally helpless .
Until all you can do is submit .
I can still hear the nuns screaming .
Even now that I 'm ...
dead .
Someone 's coming .
Who , Eri ?
There will be a new set of rules here at Sta . Lucia .
Students are not allowed to walk around , unless in pairs .
Students will be assigned to a partner
for every trip to the hallway or the washroom ,
and during recess .
Everyone must sign attendance for every class .
And most importantly ,
all faculty and students must be off the campus by 6 p.m. sharp .
Those who do not abide will be suspended ...
Do you still remember ...
the time when I had the chance to defend Ces
when she was bullied by Mary ?
- But I did nothing . - Clara don 't blame yourself .
What if you ever see me in need of help , will you come to my rescue ?
But you 're a grownup , you can take care of yourself .
Even grownups need saving sometimes .
Okay , Miss Pat .
When the time comes that you need help , I promise to be there for you .
And I promise to be there for you too .
Sor Alice ?
- Hello , Julian ? It 's me , Pat . - Hello ?
Is there any way I can talk to Fidel ?
Pat , Fidel 's case is high profile .
Not anyone can talk to him .
I just want to hear him out .
How about you ? How have you been ?
The suspect accused of strangling ...
I haven 't gotten anything yet .
It 's as if they want to forget the whole thing ,
- just to save the school 's image . - ... in the murder
of fourteen-year-old student , Clara Nemenzo ...
Sorry , Julian .
... whose body was found at 6 o 'clock in the morning by a nun in Sta . Lucia ...
Pat ? Hello ?
I 'll call you back .
We will do everything in our power
to make sure the bastard gets the death penalty .
I hope the president hears this . I hope he helps us .
We deserve justice , even if that means death for that son of a bitch .
Fidel Cariaso , the caretaker of Sta . Lucia Academy ,
is now being charged with homicide .
Clara ?
Did I startle you ?
Don 't - -
Don 't look at me .
Clara ?
Clara ...
Don 't worry .
I didn 't mean to .
Clara , who killed you ?
Someone 's coming .
Miss Consolacion !
Sor Alice ...
what are you doing here ?
Shouldn 't I be the one asking you that ?
There 's a new rule now .
No one should be here after 6 p.m.
What about you ?
I 'm just making sure no one is loitering around here .
Fidel is no longer here , and the school isn 't going to look after itself .
What happened to Clara that night you were punishing her ?
What are you trying to say , Patricia ?
Someone died that night , and we both know Fidel didn 't kill her .
If you 're going to make trouble ...
while others are still mourning ...
don 't bother coming here .
Isn 't now the time you need me the most ?
When the children don 't know what to do ?
They will know what to do if they listen .
I just want to know what happened .
I 'll give you one last chance .
Think about what you 're doing .
If I see you again around here at this hour ...
I will be forced to suspended you , Patricia .
Do you understand ?
This isn 't your purpose here .
I advise you to pray , Patricia .
So that your conscience will be cleared .
Joyce ?
Joyce !
Joyce ...
Help us !
Ms. Pat ?
What are you thinking about ?
Maybe ...
my brother .
You have a brother ?
My older brother .
Why didn 't you mention him before ?
He 's not here anymore .
He died a long time ago .
What happened to him ?
Mom and Dad weren 't around that night .
My brother and I were the only ones in the house .
And then ...
I went to his room .
Then ...
I can still remember the smell of his room .
I opened the door ...
The signs had always been there ...
but no one listened .
Joyce .
I couldn 't save my brother , Anna ...
or Clara .
But you ...
Promise me you 'll fight through this .
How is she ?
She can talk now , but she still ...
she still needs to rest for now .
Why did you come here ?
They already closed the case .
Pat , Fidel killed Clara .
There 's nothing we can do for him .
Pat .
Pat , wait .
Girls , stop .
Girls !
Don 't !
Sta . Lucia has been here for decades .
We 've been this way ever since .
Nothing has changed .
For the longest time I 've been here ,
and not once ...
did anyone question our methods .
It isn 't right to treat them that way .
All you talk about is discipline , when the children are dying .
If only you were doing your job ,
Joyce wouldn 't have attempted suicide .
- Pat , Sor Alice is only human - - - She 's blaming me for Joyce 's attempt .
I shouldn 't say this , but ...
she 's been through this before .
What happened to her student was even worse .
What happened ?
It was a long time ago . I 've only heard rumors about it .
They said the child hung herself ...
somewhere inside Sta . Lucia .
What was her name ?
I can 't remember .
It happened years ago , long before I was in Sta . Lucia .
I need your help .
- Why ? - I need access to Sor Alice 's files .
I need to know the name of the child who hung herself .
I have a feeling that this is related to what happened to Clara .
I can 't , Pat .
Even if I wanted to help , I might get suspended .
I 'll do it myself .
Pat !
I 'm already suspended .
What more can they do to me ?
Wait .
You know Erika Sayco ?
What happened to Erika ?
To Clara ?
I was a guidance counselor before .
During that time , only nuns were permitted to work in Sta . Lucia .
How do you even help someone who doesn 't want to be helped ?
Erika Sayco was like that .
The way of God was the only way I knew to help her .
But God wasn 't enough for her .
So , you gave up ?
Now I 'm starting to realize ...
that God doesn 't have all the answers .
I 'm sorry .
Then why do you keep interfering ?
Why can 't I help them in the way I know how ?
Tell Erika to forgive me .
Tell her to ask for God 's forgiveness for what she 's done .
" What she 's done ? "
Fidel wasn 't the only one there the night Clara died .
There 's a reason why spirits remain on this earth .
But I never dared to find out why .
This is what they have taught us .
I tried so hard to hide this truth ...
away from Sta . Lucia , away from Clara ,
and from you , Patricia .
There are things far too evil for us to ever understand .
Some souls are so filled with hate
that they wish nothing but harm for the living .
At that point I don 't know what to do , there 's nothing I can do !
I 'm not like you .
I won 't give up on her .
Pat !
- Pat ! - Sorry to bother you .
- Not at all . - Come inside .
I found what you asked for .
You need to see this .
- What did you find ? - With Erika , nothing .
She hung herself in the comfort room of Sta . Lucia .
That 's the only evidence I found .
It was ruled out as suicide , but I checked her father 's files ,
Ernesto Sayco .
Eri 's father ?
Two years after Eri 's death , he killed his wife .
Inside the car , outside of Sta . Lucia , he strangled her .
- That 's what she told me . - Who ?
A student of mine , she told me about this rumor .
Ernesto was sent to the electric chair .
They said he went insane after his daughter 's death .
But there was no clear motive .
I got his confession .
Listen .
Yes , I killed my wife .
Why did you kill her ?
I don 't know . I had no control over myself .
We 've argued many times , but not like this .
I was filled with rage .
A rage I 've never felt before - -
You have your tape recorder , right ?
This is Fidel 's confession .
- God help me , I didn 't mean to . - Not me , I couldn 't do this .
- Help me , I 'm not a murderer . - It 's not my fault , I couldn 't control it .
- I wrapped my hands around her neck ... - I wrapped my hands around her neck ...
- I choked the life out of her . - I choked the life out of her .
- I don 't know why I did it . - I couldn 't control myself .
- I had no control . - I don 't know why .
- Please sir , don 't throw me in jail . - I don 't know what came over me .
I have a family !
I need to go .
Wait , where are you going ?
- I need to go to Sta . Lucia . - Wait , I 'll come with you .
Why would he do it ? Why would he kill all of a sudden ?
If he really did it , why ? Where is the motive ?
- What will he get from killing her ? - Wait .
Pat , I don 't understand what you 're saying .
There 's something wrong here .
- What 's wrong ? - Everything !
- I can handle myself . - Wait , where are you going ?
- Pat ! - Thank you !
Eri ?
Why are you crying ?
It hurts .
It hurts so much .
Let 's do it this way .
I 'll go in .
You won 't see me .
I won 't see you .
But we 'll talk .
Ms. Pat , why do you keep coming back here ?
I want to find out the motive of the people who did this to you .
If I can do that , I would learn how to talk to someone like you .
People like me ?
People who were wronged .
You 'll stay with me ?
Yes , I 'll stay with you .
Always ?
Always .
You 'll follow me ...
to Hell ?
- What ? - Will you see your brother there ?
Isn 't it a sin to kill yourself ?
That 's what they taught us before .
Even Sor Alice said it .
People like me ,
should have never been born .
Eri , that 's not true .
That 's what everyone told me .
I have no friends .
No one wanted to be friends with me .
Even her .
Especially her .
No one understood me .
They wouldn 't listen .
Even at home ...
my mother cut my hair so short ...
So ... ugly .
They laughed at me .
All of them .
I wanted to die .
They say , God is always right .
No one else , only Him .
All must submit to Him .
His happiness should come first , even if we 're suffering .
I tried to leave , but they didn 't allow me .
We must all suffer for our most beloved God .
But I noticed I was the only one suffering .
So , I promised myself that one day ...
I won 't be alone in my suffering .
For God , we must come together .
My parents went to Sta . Lucia to collect the things I 'd left .
There , I discovered I could do things
that I couldn 't do while I was still alive .
My mother , she was easy to kill .
She was weak .
But my father ...
he was even weaker .
What did you do ?
You still don 't know ?
I used Fidel to kill Clara ...
so I could have a friend .
But when she was here , she didn 't want to be friends with me .
She 's like the other girls before .
Eri , what they did to you was wrong .
But this ...
Killing people ?
They killed me . They killed me every day .
Now you know ...
do you still want to be with me ?
What ?
I was okay being alone . I was contented .
But one day , you came along .
You befriended me .
You told me to get out and be friends with others .
But do you know what I found out ?
No one will ever understand me .
Not people like you !
I can 't live again ,
but you people can be like me ...
Dead .
First , Clara ...
now , you !
You 're not going to run like her , right ?
He 's coming .
Miss Pat ? Why are you running ?
Isn 't this what you wanted ?
Now we 'll know what they all say and think .
You no longer have to ask .
Eri , don 't do this , please , let 's talk . Let Julian go .
He 's coming .
Help !
Eri !
I never saw them again after that night .
Eri , or Clara .
I don 't know where they went .
It 's now quiet here at Sta . Lucia ...
Too quiet .
I don 't know what to say anymore ...
to Julian ...
to the police ...
to Sor Alice .
I don 't have anyone to talk to .
No one 's going to believe me anyway .
If Fidel really killed Clara ...
there 's nothing I can do for him ...
or for Eri .
Joyce ?
Joyce ! Joyce !
Joyce !
Miss Pa - -
Miss Pat ,
if you can hear me ...
If you can really hear me , please , help me .
Joyce !
I 'm right here , Joyce .
I 'll always be here .